Guide to the Robert Ward Papers, 1910-2012 and undated RL.01344
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Instrumental Works, 1942-2010 and undated; 4
  - Symphony No. 1, 1942-1958 and undated; 75
    - Bakersfield Symphony, digital editing by John M Proffitt, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0102)
    - Prague Chamber Orchestra, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0103)
    - Unknown performers, 2008 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0014)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0012)
    - Vienna Symphony Orchestra, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0015)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 77)
    - Orchestral score, 1942 (Box 67)
    - Conductor's score with markings, undated (Box 77)
  - Symphony No. 2, 1947-1983 and undated; 76
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1947-1983 (Box 11)
    - National Gallery Orchestra, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0104)
    - Japan Philharmonic Orchestra, 1989 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0011)
    - Electronic realization, 1999 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0038)
    - Japan Philharmonic Orchestra, 1999 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0088)
    - Japan Philharmonic Symphony Orchestra, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0006)
    - North Carolina Symphony, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0026)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 77)
    - Miniature orchestral score, 1952 (Box 67)
    - Master sheets for Serenade for Orchestra, undated (Box 77)
      Material from student work, Serenade for Orchestra was re-purposed as part of Symphony No. 2
    - Orchestral scores with markings, 1952 (Box 80)
  - Symphony No. 3, 1950-1999 and undated; 77
    Alternate title: Third Symphony
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1950-1999 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, 1984 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0030)
    - Icelandic Symphony, conducted by Igor Buketoff, 1973 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0105)
    - Iceland Symphony Orchestra, 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0006)
    - Iceland Symphony Orchestra, 1989 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0011)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0083)
    - Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra, 1954 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0014)
    - Iceland Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Igor Buketoff, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0019)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 76)
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 76)
    - Conductor's score, undated (Box 76)
    - Orchestral scores with revisions, undated; 13" x 13.5" (Box 77)
    - Orchestral score, 1958 (Box 80)
  - Symphony No. 4, 1958-1984 and undated; 78
    Alternate title: Fourth Symphony
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1958-1984 (Box 11)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Gerhardt Zimmerman, 1988 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0025)
    - Robert Ward Celebration, final edit, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0032)
    - North Carolina Symphony, version two, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0044)
    - Oratorio Singers of Charlotte, conducted by Donald Platt, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0080)
    - Albany Symphony, conducted by Julius Hegyi, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0106)
    - National Orchestral Association, conducted by John Barnett, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0107)
    - Albany Symphony, conducted by Julius Hegyi, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0108)
    - Albany Symphony, conducted by Julius Hegyi, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0012)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0109)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0017)
    - Test pressing, North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0021)
    - Unknown performers, 3 August 1958 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0023)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 77)
    - Orchestral score, unrevised, undated; 3 folders; 12.5" x 17.5" (Box 78)
      Includes unrevised scores, first revision of Mvt. III, and final revised version
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 77)
    - Orchestral score with markings, 1977-1980; 2 folders (Box 80)
  - Symphony No. 5: Canticles of America, A Psalm of Life, 1967-2002 and undated; 79
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, text, program, notes, 1967-2002 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0055)
    - Oratorio Singers of Charlotte, conducted by Donald Platt, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0080)
    - "Hymn to the Night" with Kay Lowe, soloist, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0210)
    - "Hymn to the Night" with Greensboro Choral Society and Phyllis M. Telctonidis, mezzo-soprano, 29 October 1988 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0211)
    - American Masters Concert II: The Music of Robert Ward, 10 March 2002 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0040)
    - Oratorio Singers of Charlotte, conducted by Donald Plott, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0064)
    - "Hymn to the Night," New Mobile Symphony Orchestra, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0005)
    - "Hymn to the Night," conductor's score, undated (Box 78)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 80)
    - Libretto drafts and program notes, undated (Box 80)
    - Piano-vocal score with revisions, undated; 10.5" x 12.5" (Box 78)
    - Piano-vocal scores with revisions, 1979; 2 folders (Box 80)
    - "A Psalm of Life" choral score and "Hymn to the Night" piano-vocal score, 1979 (Box 80)
    - Conductor's score, undated (Box 78)
    - Conductor's score photocopy, undated (Box 79)
  - Symphony No. 6, 1988-1991 and undated; 80
    Alternate title: Sixth Symphony
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1988-1991 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0006)
    - Brevard Concert, 15 July 1988 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0029)
    - Brevard Music Center Orchestra, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0058)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0059)
    - St. Stephens Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Lorenzo Muti, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0088)
      Only movements two and three
    - Brevard Symphony Orchestra, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0169)
    - St. Stephens Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Lorenzo Muti, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0176)
    - Triangle Chamber Orchestra, 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0006)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0044)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0083)
    - St. Stephen's Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Lorenzo Muti, 1990 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0087)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 80)
    - Orchestral scores, undated (Box 80)
  - Symphony No. 7, 2003-2004 and undated; 81
    Alternate title: Seventh Symphony
    - Programs, program notes, 2004 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0048)
    - Augusta Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Donald Portnoy, 20 March 2004 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0080)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 80)
    - Orchestral scores and program notes, 2003 (Box 80)
    - Original manuscript and photocopies, undated; 2 folders (Box 79)
  - Theme for a Radio Show, undated; 82
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 79)
  - Trio for clarinet, cello, and piano, 1998 and undated; 83
    - Program, 1998 (Box 11)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 80)
  - A Western Set from Lady Kate, 1997-2010 and undated; 84
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1997-2010 (Box 11)
    - Conducted by Pavel Prantl, takes 104-170, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0004)
    - Second movement, conducted by Pavel Prantl, takes 171-186, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0005)
    - Prague Chamber Orchestra, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0103)
    - Triangle Youth Philharmonic, 23 November 1997 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0193)
    - Czech Philharmonic Chamber Orchestra, 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0006)
    - Robert Ward compilation CD, evaluation CD #2, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0058)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0074)
    - Czech National Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Alan Balder, 20 March 2004 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0080)
    - Durham Symphony Orchestra presents a Classical Concert Honroring Composer Robert Ward, 7 March 2010 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0082)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0083)
    - Orchestral scores with revision notes and markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 80)
  - A Yankee Overture, undated; 85
    - Orchestral score master sheets and narrator text, undated (Box 79)
    - Conductor's score, undated (Box 79)
- Vocal Works, 1943-2008 and undated; 5
  Vocal Works is comprised of Robert Ward's pieces for solo voice, choir, spoken narrator, and chorus with larger ensemble combinations. Some works include newspaper clippings, programs, and reviews from performances. Many of the pieces include music sketches, drafts of texts, some correspondence, piano-vocal scores, full scores, orchestral scores, conductor's scores, complete sets of parts, and recordings when noted. Media types include audiocassettes, compact discs, digital audio tapes, DVDs, and VHS tapes. The scores include published versions, edited proofs—many in Ward's own hand—master sheets, printing masters, and original manuscripts. Recording titles are taken from the media objects themselves. Arranged alphabetically by title of piece.
  - Aria Anthologies, 1993-2003; 90
    - William Stone Sings Arias from Operas by Robert Ward, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0157)
    - William Stone Sings Arias and Songs by Robert Ward, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0158)
    - Recording I, Arias and Songs, 15 April 1991 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0170)
    - Recording II, Arias and Songs, 15 April 1991 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0171)
    - Stone, Tom Warburton, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0215)
    - Bill Stoxe, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0216)
    - World Premiere Recording, William Stone, baritone, and Thomas Warburton, piano, 1991 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0013)
    - Robert Ward: Arias and Songs, William Stone, baritone, undated (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0093)
    - Robert Ward: Arias and Songs, 1991 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0096)
    - Robert Ward: Arias and Songs, William Stone, baritone, 1991 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0097)
    - Piano-vocal scores and sheet music, 1993-2003 (Box 80)
      Baritone piano-vocal score, tenor and mezzo piano-vocal score edited proofs; includes arias from Abelard and Heloise, Claudia Legare, The Crucible, He Who Gets Slapped (Pantaloon), The Lady from Colorado, Lady Kate, Minutes Till Midnight
  - Cherish Your Land, 2000-2001 and undated; 91
    - North Carolina of Natural Sciences opening ceremony, 7 April 2000 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0166)
    - Mallarmé Chamber Players, National Opera Company, conducted by Robert Ward, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0213)
    - NCMNS opening ceremonies, 7 April 2000 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0012)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 80)
    - Full score, piano-vocal score, choral score, 2001 and undated (Box 80)
  - Concord Hymn, 1979 and undated; 92
    - Choral Music of Robert Ward, The Belmont Chorale, 1995 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0085)
    - Music sketches, choral score, 1979 and undated (Box 80)
  - Earth Shall Be Fair, 1960-2000 and undated; 93
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1960-2000 (Box 11)
    - Wilmington, Delaware Earth Day, 27 April 1997 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0016)
    - Belmont Chorale, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0046)
    - Depauw Chorus and Orchestra, conducted by Robert Ward, 3 May 1992 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0181)
    - Depauw Chorus and Orchestra, conducted by Robert Ward, 3 May 1992 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0182)
    - Depauw Chorus and Orchestra, conducted by Robert Ward, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0064)
    - Choral Music of Robert Ward, The Belmont Chorale, 1995 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0085)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0044)
    - Premiere, conducted by Robert Ward, La Jolla, California, 3 August 1958 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0023)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0029)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0043)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 80)
    - Organ part, original manuscript of mvt. II, undated (Box 80)
    - Choral score, "Would Ye Be Glad and Wise", 1960 (Box 80)
    - Piano-vocal scores with some markings, 1960; 2 folders (Box 80)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 80)
  - Five Songs, 1944-2005 and undated; 94
    "Sorrow of Mydath," "Anna Miranda," "Rain Has Fallen All the Day," "As I Watched the Ploughman Ploughing," "Vanished"
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, 1944-2005 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 32, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0049)
    - Piano scores, edited copies, incomplete master sheets, music sketches, 1952 and undated (Box 80)
      Includes high and low voice versions of all songs
  - The Hill, 1995-1996 and undated; 95
    - Programs, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Downtown Music Production, Sixth Annual Benson Aids Series, 1 December 1995 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0036)
    - Susan Dunn, soprano, and Randy Love, piano, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0137)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 81)
    - Piano-vocal scores, high and low voice versions, 1995 and undated; 2 folders (Box 81)
  - A Home at Last for Opera, 2012; 96
    - Music sketches, text drafts, correspondence, piano-vocal score, 2012 (Box 81)
  - Hush'd be the Camps Today, 1943-2001; 97
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, 1946-1951 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0053)
    - University of Wisconsin students and faculty, September 1989 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0065)
    - Hush'd Be the Camps Today, no dolby, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0209)
    - Oslo Philharmonic Orchestra, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0010)
    - Choral scores, 1943-2001 (Box 81)
  - Images of God, 1988-1990 and undated; 98
    - Images of God Correspondence, 1988 (Box 6)
      Correspondence regarding first performance at Duke Chapel
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Voice of God by Clay Taliaferro, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0043)
    - "Consider Well God's Ways," Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0053)
    - Duke University Chapel, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0191)
    - Voice of God tape, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0192)
    - "In His Last Days Jesus Came to Jerusalem," "Let us Heed the Voice Within," Choral Music of Robert Ward, The Belmont Chorale, 1995 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0085)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0007)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0008)
    - Images of God copy, 19 February 1989 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0011)
    - V/O master show tape, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0002)
    - V/O safety master, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0003)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 81)
    - Text and program drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Incomplete copy of original manuscript, undated (Box 81)
    - Piano-vocal scores of individual movements, incomplete, 1990 (Box 81)
      "In His Last Days Jesus Came to Jerusalem," "Let Us Heed the Voice Within," "Consider Well God's Ways"
    - Master sheets, undated; 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Full scores, 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 81)
      Includes original photocopy
  - In Praise of Science, 2008 and undated; 99
    - Program, program notes, 2008 (Box 11)
    - Music sketches and text drafts, undated (Box 81)
    - Piano-vocal score and full score, 2008; 2 folders (Box 81)
  - The Lamb, 2007-2008; 100
    - Program, 2007 (Box 11)
    - World Premiere, Duke University String School and Durham Children's Choir, 8 December 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0024)
    - Full score and complete parts, piano-vocal score, 2008 (Box 81)
  - Let the Word Go Forth, 1964-1965 and undated; 101
    - Program, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Music sketches and text drafts, letter, 1964 and undated (Box 81)
  - Love's Seasons, 1994-2001 and undated; 102
    - Newspaper clipping, programs, program notes, 1994-2001 (Box 11)
    - Marilyn Taylor, soprano, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0138)
    - Sandra McClain, soprano, and Margo Garrett, piano, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0199)
    - Kay Lowe, soprano, and James Dupre, piano, 17 September 1995 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0200)
    - Marilyn Taylor, voice, and Robert Brewer piano, 26 March 2000 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0021)
    - Marilyn Taylor, voice, and Robert Brewer piano, 6 June 2000 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0041)
    - Art Songs from Carolina; Marilyn Taylor, soprano, and Robert Brewer, piano, 2001 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0079)
    - Love's Seasons: Songs of Mary Howe and Robert Ward, Sandra McClain and Margo Garrett, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0084)
    - Music sketches and original manuscript, undated (Box 81)
    - Piano-vocal scores, 1994; 2 folders (Box 81)
      Includes copy of song texts and program notes
    - Master sheets, original key, 1994 (Box 81)
  - Sacred Canticles for Chorus, Organ, Trumpet and Percussion, undated; 105
    - William Ferris Chorale, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0054)
    - Music sketches and drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Full scores with markings and complete parts, undated (Box 81)
  - Sacred Songs for Pantheists, 1951-2004; 106
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1951-2004 (Box 11)
    - Master's Thesis on Sacred Songs for Panthesists, 1963 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, 1984 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0030)
    - University of Wisconsin students and faculty, September 1992 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0064)
    - University of Delaware Brass, Dan Pressler and wife, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0066)
    - Polish National Radio Orchestra, conducted by William Strickland, 1973 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0105)
    - Carolyn Stevens, North Carolina Composers' Recital, Crawford Hall, North Carolina School of the Arts, 29 April 1990 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0110)
    - The Polish National Radio Orchestra, conducted by William Strickland, 2000 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0004)
    - Louisville Orchestra, 1989 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0066)
    - Iceland Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Igor Buketoff, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0019)
    - Piano-vocal scores with some markings, 1966-1996 (Box 81)
    - Orchestral score, 1995 (Box 81)
  - Search Me, O God, and Know My Heart, 1997; 107
    - Program, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Songs for Ravenscroft, 1992-1994 and undated; 108
    - Program, letter, 1992-1994 (Box 11)
    - Premiere, 5 November 1993 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0082)
    - Anthem, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0039)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 82)
    - Orchestral score, 1993 (Box 82)
    - Choruses, piano-vocal scores, 1993 (Box 82)
  - Sweet Freedom's Song, 1965-1986 and undated; 109
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, poster, 1968-1986 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0055)
    - Lexington Choral Society, conducted by Allen Lannon, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0098)
    - Lexington Choral Society, conducted by Allen Lannom, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0012)
    - Choral Music of Robert Ward, The Belmont Chorale, 1995 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0085)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0044)
    - Premiere, parts 1-4, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0021)
    - Premiere, parts 5-7, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0022)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0043)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 82)
    - Libretto and drafts of program notes, undated (Box 82)
    - Choral scores, individual movements, 1965 (Box 82)
      "It was a Great Design," "Ballad of Boston Bay," "Epitaphs," "Sweet Freedom's Song"
    - Piano-vocal score, 1966 (Box 82)
  - That Wondrous Night of Christmas Eve, 1957-2007; 110
    - Programs, 2004-2007 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0053)
    - University of Wisconsin students and faculty, September 1989 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0065)
    - With Heart and Voice: Christmas Across America, 1996 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0010)
    - Choral scores, 1957 (Box 82)
  - Three Songs, undated; 111
    "I Know a Quiet Vale," "Daphne," "My Soul is Like a Garden Close"
    - Original manuscripts and copies, undated (Box 82)
  - Three Pieces for Narrator and Piano, 1957-1991 and undated; 112
    Poems of T.S. Eliot: "The Song of the Jellicles," "Mr. Mistoffelees," "Of the Awefull Battle of the Pekes and the Pollicles"
    - Programs, 1957-1991 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0062)
    - Music sketches and piano scores, "Of the Awefull Battle of the Pekes and the Pollicles", 1991 and undated (Box 82)
  - We're Gonna Have a Great Big Celebration, undated; 113
    - Program, undated (Box 11)
  - When Christ Rode into Jerusalem, 1957-1974; 114
    - Programs, 1957-1974 (Box 11)
    - Belmont Chorale, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0046)
    - Choral Music of Robert Ward, The Belmont Chorale, 1995 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0085)
    - Choral scores and original master sheets, 1957 (Box 82)
  - With Rue My Heart is Laden, 1950-1951 and undated; 115
    - Programs, 1950-1951 (Box 11)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0053)
    - Choral scores, undated (Box 82)
- Music Sketchbooks and Student Works, undated; 6
  Music Sketchbooks and Student Works contains assorted untitled music sketches and sketchbooks by Robert Ward, some of which may be related to later published works. Also includes score and parts to Ward's withdrawn work, his 1st String Quartet (not to be confused with his First String Quartet from 1966), and libretto drafts to a work entitled The Tragic Muse. Also contains various contrapuntal exercises from Ward's time at the Eastman School of Music, as well as orchestrations of works by J.S. Bach and Claude Debussy. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - 1st String Quartet (withdrawn work), full score and incomplete parts, undated (Box 85)
  - Assorted music sketchbooks, undated; 3 folders (Box 82)
  - Assorted untitled sketches, undated (Box 82)
  - Assorted student works and music exercises, undated (Box 82)
  - Early sketches, prior to Eastman School of Music attendance, undated (Box 85)
  - Early songs: Die Lustige Witwe, Spirit Square, Grof/Marshall, 6 May 1980 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0083)
  - Early songs: Grof/Marshall, May 1980 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0084)
  - Orchestrations of works by J.S. Bach and Claude Debussy, undated (Box 85)
  - Piece titled "Energetically", undated (Box 85)
  - The Tragic Muse, libretto sketches, undated (Box 82)
  - Untitled sketch, undated (Box 85)
    Includes text: "Bill S., U.S. Education Commission"
- Music by Others, 1910-2007 and undated; 7